# Immaculate Eseosa Lawrence

### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

FHA Lugbe Airport Road Abuja, Nigeria (+234) 8124041440

Email - ese.imhariagbe@gmail.com

linkedIn - www.linkedin.com/in/ese-lawrence

Github - https://github.com/koimasshiro Twitter - https://twitter.com/codewithkoi

## **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Solution-driven Software Engineer adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment and finding solutions. Proven experience developing consumer focused websites and web applications using React.js, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Node.js, MongoDb, Python, C#, MVC and .NET. Good knowledge of the best practices for web design, user experience, speed, solving code problems and speed.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Freelancing, Abuja, Nigeria - Web designer

FEBRUARY 2021 - DECEMBER 2022

- Worked with clients to gather and define requirements, establish scopes and manage project milestones.
- Built a maintainable and stable codespaces using React.
- Stayed current for industry trends for websites, user friendliness and database driven web applications.
- Worked in a team environment with Writers, Graphic Designers and Backend Developers.
- Planning Site designs, functionality and navigation.
- Creating Landing pages using React.js and Html/CSS

IngleSwitch, Lagos, Nigeria - Full Stack Engineer Intern

JANUARY 2023 - MARCH 2023

- Wrote clean, efficient, and maintainable code using .NET technologies such as C#, ASP.NET, and SQL Server.
- I learned new skills and technologies to improve my abilities as a .NET developer.
- Collaborated with other team members to understand requirements, identify potential issues, and develop solutions.

- Participated in code reviews and contributed to the team's codebase.
- Testing and debugging code to ensure that applications are functioning as intended.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Seed International School - SSCE

SEPTEMBER 2016 - MARCH 2019

## Alt School - Diploma

School of Engineering
FEBRUARY 2023 - MARCH 2024

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- <u>freeCodeCamp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures</u>
- <u>freeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design</u>
- Sololearn Python core
- Introduction to C#
- C# Intermediate
- SQL Intermediate
- React + Redux
- jQuery

## **PROJECTS**

- e-Commerce website that accepts Crypto payments with React.js,
   TypeScript, web3 React and CSS
- Social Media web application called 'Howfa' with MERN.
- E-Commerce Microservices in .Net
- MVC Authentication using Identity
- Personal Portfolio webpage
- Landing Pages
- KudiTrack Expense Tracker
- Web API for User registration, Authentication and Authorization in .NET

## **SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS
- C#
- .Net
- SQL
- Azure
- MongoDB
- React.js
- MVC
- Node.js
- Bootstrap
- Innovative problem solving
- ExpressJs
- Python
- Attention to details
- Responsive Design